Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

[Electronics/Telecommunication]

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.



A motivated and skilled professional with 2.2 years of experience in Python, Django, Django-Rest framework, mySQL, Data structures and Algorithms (problem solving).



Current Designation: Software Engineer

Current Company: Dell International Services India Private

Limited

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore,Pune,Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: MySQL,OOP, Jenkins, Python Developer, Python, Version Control, Data

Structures, Algorithms, Django, Panda, Problem Solving, Backend Developer, API, Web Services, Rest

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 2-Dec-20 Last Modified: 2-Dec-20

Summary

I am a self-motivated and skilled Professional with over 2 yrs. of experience in Backend Development using python. I can write well organised, bug free clean code using self-developed strong problem-solving ability and decision-making skills to meet tight deadlines.

Like to work independently or as a team with helpful and cooperative nature as well

Work Experience

Dell International Services India Private Limited as Software Engineer Feb 2020 to Till Date

reb 2020 to Till Date

I was working on dell Internal project DURM whose main work is to monitor the repository of all projects and scans if committed codes have any vulnerability or third party Licenses etc.

I was mainly working on Django implementation and Rest-Api part

Huawei Technologies as Associate Software Engineer Jun 2018 to Jan 2020

Currently working as a Automation engineer where we modify test scripts according to design specifications for Android devices running on EMUI:

I work on modifying /writing new test scripts on GUI level.

- # I work in pipeline team also for executing all automated cases and Debug the failed cases using Jenkins logs.
- # I manage all the Head versions coming form different channel and operators.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT) in 2017

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Software Intern at Hexaware Technologies, Chennai, as a full Stack Developer

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
MySQL		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Python	3.7+	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Jenkins	5.1.6	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Eclipse	4.5.2	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
DJANGO	3.1.1	2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Django Rest Framework		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Problem solving		0	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Web Crawler Client: SELF WORK

Nature of Employment: Part Time Duration: Oct 2020 - Oct 2020

Project Location: https://github.com/RanjanDash- Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

projects/webcrawler Role: Programmer

Obilitional Distance Multithe

Skill Used: Python, Multithreading

Role Description: During execution first thread will run and collect links to the homepage and then triggers multiple threads simultaneously which will go into each searched URL and collect data and write all links to the file. And all searched links to another file.

Team Size: 1

Project Details: # Languages: Python3, (Concepts: Multithreading, file handling, and requests)

Summary: This is a desktop app that takes a BASE_URL of any website and crawls through that website to provide all links on that website, we can use it for getting specific data files from the website as well (though some code modification required).

Role: Developer,

The main objective is to efficiently use multithreading in python for improving performance.

Project Title: OSS (Open Source Scan)

Client: Dell

Nature of Employment: Contractual

Project Location: Dell International Services

Role: Programmer

Duration: Feb 2020 - Jul 2020
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 5

Skill Used: python, Django,pandas, My SQL

Role Description: Working as a Security Automation Engineer, where I audit the git/ SVN commits codes to find the

vulnerabilities.

Project Details: I have worked on OSS tool (like DURM tool) where I modified functionality in Tool for scanning different open source license along with the vulnerabilities.

Project Title: Android Automation Client: Huawei Technologies Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Mar 2018 - Jun 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Location: Banglore

Role: Programmer Team Size: 14

Skill Used: Python, Python shell Scripting, Debugging, Jenkins, Android ADB commands, GUI Automation.

Role Description: #. Our team modify/write test scripts according to product requirements specifications for Android devices

running on EMUI - 8.2, 9.0, 9.1.

#. I work in pipeline team for executing all automated cases and Debug failed cases using Jenkins logs.

Project Details: # I am working under Handsets team so our major focus remains upon system UI or EMUI modification across all operators and channel countries.

I have worked on basic functional requirements for new EMUI released (EMUI: 8.2, 9.0 and 9.1)

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time